

# Mohammad ali Ali panah

Software Engineer 20 years old

mohammadali.ap.2000@gmail.com +989197532677



https://linkedin.com/in/tur1ng





# **Story Book**

As a child, I grow up with endless love of computers. Started learning HTML, CSS, and JQuery at the age of 13 in MFT. Couldn't catch up back then because of poor knowledge of fundamentals, So I continued my journey several years later by learning C++ and Javascript in depth. this time was different and I feel the improvement every day. Nowadays, I spend most of my time at work structuring and building reusable components and maintainable codes, also, spend free time reading books about system architecture and clean coding.

# **Recent Experience**

### React Developer

KIAN IRANIAN STDG - Full-time

Aug 2020 – Present Tehran, Iran

- Rewriting the web client of iGap messenger with Reactis, Typescript, Redux, WebSocket and Material-Ui. I wrote around 40% of codebase. Structure Redux and other Logics. Converting class component to functional, groups, channels, forward message, iLand, authentication pages, setting tab, sticker, animated stickers, some of message boxes, many resuble components and utils are a part of my job. Currently planning for Beta release (https://igap.net/web2).
- Coding parsian-club with React, Typescript, Emotion, React-Query. Currently in testing phase.
- Suggesting and coding some part of iGap Doc (https://doc.igap.net/docs/Introduction) with Docusaurus v2, mdx,
- Coding (https://stickerprize.igap.net) in less than a day
- helping to build some internal tools and Back-End panels.

#### **React Developer**

Mine Taxi - Part-time Apr 2020 - Jul 2020 Tehran, Iran

MineTaxi (http://minetaxi.ir) is a ride-hailing startup. Great first step as developer.

- Building an E-commerce website from ground up.
- React for building user interfaces and Sass for styling.
- Using Redux for state management and cart functionality. due to the coronavirus, the side project did lunch properly.

# **Education**

### **Babol Noshirvani University of Technology**

Bachelor's degree - Computer Software Engineering 2019 - 2023

Babol, Iran

Working on collections-typescript, an open source project to bring fast and tested algorithm and data structure to typescript such as LinkedList, Doubly LinkedList, Tree and breadth and depth first search, and all kind of sorting algorithm (https://github.com/always-maap/Collections-TypeScript)

planning to restructure with mono-repos and lerna.

# Technical Skills (in order)

### **Software Engineering**

Typescript, Ecmascript, Python, Git, Docker, Eslint, Babel, Yarn, Lerna

#### Client (proficient)

React, Redux, styled-components, Sass, CSS, HTML, react-query, react-hook-form, react-native, PWA workbox

### Industry

Data Structes, Algorithm, OOP, Command & Shell, MVC, DRY, SOLID, Microservices, MonoRepos, TDD, Design Patterns

#### Server (familiar)

Nodejs, GraphQL, Apollo Server, MongoDB, MySQL, Mongoose, Type ORM

# Soft Skills



# **Book and Cources**

- The Pragmatic Programmer Andy Hunt and Dave Thomas
- Introduction to Algorithms Thomas H. Cormen (some chapters)
- SOLID: The Software Design and Architecture Khalil Stemmler
- AlgoExpert Clement Mihailescu (currently watching)
- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Masterclass Colt Steele
- Microservices with Node IS and React Stephen Grider
- Compelte intro to React, Intermediate Brian Holt
- Epic React Kent C. Dodds
- Production grade Typescript, MonoRepos Mike North
- Head First Design Patters Freeman and Sierra (currently reading)

# Interests



